Guide to the István Deák Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
István Deák Papers,
1960-1995.
Deák, István.
9.89 linear ft. (14 document boxes, 3 record cartons, 1 microfilm box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1568
8644506
The István Deák papers document the scholarly activities of István Deák, a professor of History at Columbia University from 1964-1997 and director of the Harriman Institute on East Central Europe from 1968 to 1979.
Biographical Note
István Deák, the Seth Low Professor Emeritus of History, was born in Hungary in 1926, and in 1948 emigrated to France and studied history at the Sorbonne. From 1948 to 1956, he worked in France and Germany as a journalist and librarian and moved to New York in 1956, to pursue his Ph.D. at Columbia University. He received it in 1964, with a dissertation entitled "Weimar Germany's 'Homeless Left': The World of Carl Von Ossietzky." Deák taught at Columbia from 1964 until his retirement in 1997, with some brief appointments at other universities. He was also the director of the Institute on East Central Europe from 1968 to 1979. After his retirement, Deák continued to teach at Columbia as a lecturer and worked at Stanford in 2002.
Professor Deák's research concentrates on 20th century central and east central Europe. He has published a number of works, including Weimar Germany's Left-wing Intellectuals: A Political History of the "Weltbuhne" and Its Circle (The University of California Press, 1968); The Lawful Revolution: Louis Kossuth and the Hungarians, 1848-1849 (Columbia University Press, 1979),Beyond Nationalism: A Social and Political History of the Habsburg Officer Corps, 1848-1918 (Oxford University Press, 1990), Essays on Hitler's Europe (University of Nebraska Press, 2001), and edited The Politics of Retribution in Europe: World War II and Its Aftermath (Princeton University Press, 2000). Deak has received a number of prizes for his work including the Lionel Trilling Book Award, the Way S. Vucinich Book Prize of the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, the John S. Guggenheim Fellowship, and he was a fellow at the Institute for Advanced Study at Princeton, the Woodrow Wilson Center and the Institute for Human Sciences in Vienna Austria.
Scope and Content
The István Deák Papers document his professional life, with a particular focus on his work during the 1980s and 1990s. The majority of the papers are comprised of articles, essays, conference programs and lectures. There are also two large groups of research notes, one set of research contributing to his PhD dissertation on intellectuals in the Weimar Republic, the other a large collection of data sheets related to Hungarian soldiers in the Habsburg Army. The collection is intellectually arranged by series, including scholarly writing, teaching and administrative activities, conferences and lectures, and research notes in two sections. However, the collection retains its original physical order reflecting Deák's arrangement of the files. Many of the original folders with Deák's extensive notes have also been retained and kept with the files they originally held.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in five series
Series I. Scholarly Writing, 1963-1996
Subseries I.1. Articles and Essays, 1967-1996
Subseries I.2. Correspondence, 1982-1991
Subseries I.3. Projects, 1986-1994
Subseries I.4. Book Reviews and Manuscripts Read for Publishers, 1966-1996
Subseries I.5. PhD Dissertation, 1963-1969
Series II. Teaching and Administrative Activities, 1964-1986
Subseries II.1. Student Papers and Class Lectures, undated
Subseries II.2. Notes, 1971-1986
Subseries II.3. Booklists, Sources, Syllabi, 1964-1967
Series III. Conferences and Lectures, 1969-1994
Series IV. Habsburg Army Research Notes, undated
Subseries IV.1. Data Sheets and Calculations, undated
Subseries IV.2. Research Notes, undated
Series V. Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbuhne and its Causes, 1930-1970
Subseries V.1. Research Notes, 1962-1968
Subseries V.2. Die Weltbühne, 1930
Subseries V.3. Administrative Files, 1963-1970
Subjects
Columbia University--Alumni and Alumnae.; Columbia University--Faculty.; Deák, István.; Military Historians.; Historians--Hungary.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Historians.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Series II, Box 13, Folders 10 and 11 and Box 17 folder 9 contain student papers and are restricted until 2035.
Acquisition
István Deák Gift 07/13/1999
István Deák Gift 12/28/2008 2008.2009.M012
- Series I: Scholarly Writing, 1963-1996
  This series contains documents related to Deak's published and unpublished scholarly writing. It documents his professional life, particularly the relationships he had in the intellectual community, and his professional status in the study of the history of central Europe as a contributor and editor.
  - Subseries I.1: Articles and Essays, 1967-1996
    Deak wrote many articles, and kept copies of those articles as well as their reviews from other publications. There are a number of drafts and published copies of articles. The files also contain correspondence regarding articles and that Deak worked on, copies of reviews of his work and letters in response to negative and positive reviews of his work.
    - Articles and Essays, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Essays, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Articles and Essays, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Articles and Essays, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Articles and Essays, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Articles and Essays, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Essays, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles and Essays, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Essays--"Revolution, Progress and Decline: Hungary Between 1848 and 1918," undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Articles and Essays, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Articles and Essays, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Articles and Essays--"Rosen Manuscript, Habsburg Monarchy: A Complex Patrimony,” Conference, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Articles and Essays--German Unification, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Articles and Essays, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Articles and Essays, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Articles and Essays, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Articles and Essays, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Essays--The American Historical Review, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Articles and Essays--Review of "The Contested Country," #113, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Essays--"The Making of Modern Freedom" Washington University St. Louis 992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Articles and Essays--"The Ethnic Question in the Multinational Habsburg Army," 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Articles and Essays--Review of "Budapest and New York," 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Articles and Essays--New York Times Book Review, Balkan Ghosts: A Tourney Through History," 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Articles and Essays, circa 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Articles and Essays--Szazadok, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Articles and Essays--The European Right: A Historical Profile Review, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Articles and Essays--Germany, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Articles and Essays--Germany, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subseries I.2. Correspondence, 1982-1991
    The correspondence covers various academic topics, some related to articles and books that Deak was working on, conference organizing, and his response to other people's work. Deak corresponds with academics and publishers, almost entirely on work-related subjects.
    - Correspondence--Grothusen, K.D., 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence--Sugar, Peter, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence--Carl Beck Papers, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence--"The Habsburg Army in Memoir Literature," 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--Solomon Wank, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence--Jean-Paul Bled, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subseries I.3. Projects, 1986-1994
    This subseries is related to Deak's academic projects other than publication. In 1991, Deak helped organize an exhibition of the Hugarian Avant-Garde at the Santa Barbara Museum of Art, and provided an essay for the book describing the context for Hungarian artists working from 1908-1930. Deak also provided a number of entries to encyclopedias.
    - Projects--Hungarian Avant-Garde, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Projects--Encyclopedia Entries, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.4. Book Reviews and Manuscripts Read for Publishers, 1966-1996
    Deak wrote many reviews of other people's work, and this series contains a number of formal reviews he published in journals, and informal peer reviews for publishers. The files contain drafts, publisher's preprints, and final copies of reviews. There is also correspondence with publishers and other scholars, and reactions to his reviews. Deak was also very active in peer reviews for books. He read many articles for journals, publishers, and foundations. In many cases he read the articles anonymously
    - Book Reviews, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Book Reviews, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Book Reviews, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews, 1966-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Book Reviews, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews, 1981-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Book Reviews, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Book Reviews, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Book Reviews, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Book Reviews, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Book Reviews, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Book Reviews, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I.5. PhD Dissertation, 1963-1969
    This subseries contains Deak's PhD dissertation. He finished his degree in 1964, and the dissertation eventually became his first book Weimer Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes.
    - Ph.D. Dissertation, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Correspondence--Dissertation, 1963-1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Series II. Teaching and Administrative Activities, 1964-1986
  Deak was an active teacher, teaching classes on the history of central and east central Europe. This series contains lecture notes, student papers, and various other notes related to his scholarly and teaching activities.
  - Subseries II.1. Student Papers and Class Lectures, undated
    The series contains lectures on a variety of subjects including the Enlightenment, the French Revolution, various philosophers, the Industrial Revolution, and Adam Smith. Most of the lectures come from a class entitled Contemporary Civilization that Deak taught in the spring of 1965. Deak also retained a few student papers that he found particularly interesting.
    - Research Notes, Lectures, Student Papers, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
      [Restricted until 2035]
    - Research Notes, Lectures, Student Papers, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes, Lectures, Student Papers, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes, Lectures, Student Papers, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.2. Notes, 1971-1986
    The notes relate to Deak's teaching and administrative activities. Among the notes are a series of letters and notes where Deak was involved in bringing the papers of Jaromir Smutny, the chancellor to President Benes of Czechoslovakia into the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at Columbia University. It also contains notes from secondary sources related to his teaching and research.
    - Notecards (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Notes--Smutny Papers, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Notes--Koplin, Grossman, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Notes--Stephen Kertesz Memorial, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II.3.Booklists, Sources, Syllabi, 1964-1967
    This subseries contains a syllabus for a course Deak taught in 1964. He also kept bibliographies from published works related to the classes, and citations of books, as well as guides to archives in his field. There are also lists of suggested books that Deak sent to colleagues interested in topics related to his research.
    - Booklists, Sources, Syllabi, 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series III. Conferences and Lectures, 1969-1994
  This series makes up the bulk of the papers. Deak kept extensive notes on all of the lectures that he gave across the country, and many detailed records about his activities at conferences. This series includes lecture notes, programs from various conferences, invitations to attend, correspondence regarding lectures and attendance, administrative files, and itineraries related to conference attendance.
  - Conferences and Lectures--Bellagio Conference, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures--The Age of Revolutions, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Suceava Conference, Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Wilson Center Lecture, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Bucharest Conference, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Magyarsa's Conference, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures--USIA-IREX Conference, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The History of the Rhine," undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Baltic Cruise Lectures, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Danube Trip, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Conference and Lectures--"Society and Culture in a Multi-Ethnic Environment: The Case of Transylvania," 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Historical Conference of Fascism," 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Brooklyn College Conference on Society in Change," 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"War and Society," 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Austria and the Two Europes," Harvard University, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Workshop on Eastern Europe," University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--IREX-Budapest Conference, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--University of Minnesota, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Conferences and Lectures--IREX Conference, Carnegie Corporation, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The Danger of Anti-Semitism in Hungary," Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Leo Baeck Institute, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Comprehending the Incomprehensible," Branham Lecture, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Duquense University, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The End of the Empire," Harriman Institute, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Hungarian Institute, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The Fall of the Habsburg and Soviet Empires," The Prague Central European University Foundation, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Minneapolis Symposium, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Baltic Cruise, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The Fall of Austria-Hungary and Peace, Stability and Legitimacy," Nobel Symposium, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Revolutions of 1848," Ohio Northern University, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures--University of Montana, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Sobering Days in Hungary," Conference on Eastern Europe, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Institute for Human Sciences, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Budapest, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The Fall of the Soviet and Hungarian Empires," Institut Universitaire de Hautes Etudens Internationales, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"The Fall of the Habsburg and Soviet Empires: An Attempted Comparison," Das Institut für den Donauraum und Mitteleuropa, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Political Groups, Social Classes and Social Issues in Weimar Germany," University of Minnesota, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Conferences and Lectures--University of Minnesota, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Second Conference of Polish and American Historians," University of Iowa, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Faces of Tradition; Germany in Europe--The Last Hundred Years," Smith College, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Revolutionary Situations in Europe: 1917-1922 Germany, Italy, Austria-Hungary," Interuniversity Center for European Studies, Montreal, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"East-West Forum," 1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Federalist Ideas in East Central Europe During the Interwar Years," AAASS, Boston, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Re-thinking Eastern European History," New College, Sarasota, Florida, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Vanderbilt University, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"What Can History Teach us About Change in Eastern Europe," The Washington Institute, D.C., 1989 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"In Search of Central Europe," The Wilson Center, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Jews in European Society and Politics, 1918-1945," American Historical Association, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"East Central Europe and Superpower Politics Between the Moscow Talks in October 1944 and the Prague Spring in 1968," York University, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Military History Symposium, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Minnesota Conferences on Jews in Austria, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--German Studies Association, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--East European Program, The Wilson Center, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"East European Fascism in World War II," Institute on International Change, Columbia University, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Chivalry, Gentlemanly Honor, and Virtuous Ladies in Austria-Hungary," Robert A. Kann Memorial Lecture, University of Minnesota, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Democratizing Eastern Europe: Illusion or Reality," National Defense University, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Conferences and Lectures--Hungary, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Conferences and Lectures--IREX, Romania, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"Central Europe: Past, Present, Future," Vienna, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Conferences and Lectures--"From Europe to Europe: 1,100 Years of Hungarian History," The Smithsonian Institution, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Habsburg Army Research Notes, undated
  The research notes in this collection contain detailed information on over 1000 soldiers in the Habsburg Army, as well a numerous notes on the materials written in Hungarian. In the course of his research, Deak created a number of calculations and written documents analyzing the data. In 1990, Deak published Beyond Nationalism: A Social and Political History of the Habsburg Officer Corps.
  - Subseries IV.1. Data Sheets and Calculations, undated
    The data sheets are written in Hungarian and English, and detail each veteran's name, vital statistics, residence, religion, and other details of his life during and after service. Deak particularly analyzed soldiers who came from the nobility.
    - Data Sheets and Calculations, undated (Box 15, Folder 1 to 9)
    - Data Sheets and Calculations--Noble Officers, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Data Sheets and Calculations, undated (Box 15, Folder 11 to 15)
    - Data Sheets--Kuk Army, The Wilson Center, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Data Sheets and Calculations, undated (Box 15, Folder 17 to 27)
  - Subseries IV.2. Research Notes, undated
    These research notes are particularly related to the research he was doing on the Habsburg Officer corps. He looked at different groups of officers in different ways, with particular interest in education, nobility, Jews and Hungarians.
    - Research Notes--Szolnoky Anyag, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes--Qua-Listen Instruction Samples, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes--Pictures sent to Vienna, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes--Jews in the Habsburg Army-1849 undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes--Jews in the Austrian and Austro-Hungarian Armies-1849-1918 undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes--1000 Officers, Special Cases, Court Records, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes--Military Education, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes--Regimental Histories, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Research Notes--Military History, undated (Box 16, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Research Notes--Hungarian, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes--Statistics from Yearbook, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes--1000 Officers Statistics, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Research Notes--Duplicate Statistics, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Research Notes--Militar Statisches Jarbuch, undated (Box 16, Folder 15 to 23)
    - Research Notes--Memoirs, A-L, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes--Memoirs, M-Z, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, A-C, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)